#### Contact

+8801874632327 (Mobile) rafsan.ahmad.iut@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rafsanahmad-943543105 (LinkedIn) rafsanahmad.github.io/ (Personal)

### Top Skills

Java

Android

Kotlin

### Languages

Bangla (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

#### Certifications

Kotlin Essential Training: Functions, Collections, and I/O

Advanced iOS App Development: MapKit & Core Location

Agile Project Leadership

iOS 15 Development Essential Training

Bachelor of Science

#### Honors-Awards

Full scholarship for 4 years of undergraduate study

Higher Secondary Level Education Board Scholarship

GP TELENOR youth forum

EATL app competition

Top StackOverflow Answerer

# Rafsan Ahmad

Lead Engineer at Samsung R&D, SRBD Bangladesh

## Summary

Mobile Application developer with over 6 years of professional experience, mostly utilizing Java and Kotlin based frameworks.

I possess a wide range of skills in the field of software technologies. I have strong knowledge in different Mobile related technologies, for iOS and Android app development.

I also learn toward using and combining new open source technologies in my work. I am able to take responsibility in a team for any mobile development project for design and development.

I like to work in an environment where an opportunity for selfassessment and improvement in both individual and group-based jobs that frequently face various critical challenges and serves the community with individual skills that is present.

#### Core skills:

- Java, Kotlin, Swift, Dart
- Mobile Application development
- Problem Solving
- Optimised Code Architecture & Best Practices
- Research, Analysis and Planning
- Teamwork
- Communication
- Debug & Bug Fixing
- App Performance Optimisation
- MVVM / MVP
- OOP
- Agile

## Work Experience

Samsung R&D Institute, Bangladesh

Lead Engineer

February 2022 - Present (9 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Working on Samsung Smart-Things project and building different functionality for IoT connected devices.

My responsibilities include:

- a. Working on Smart-Things app Location module to manage location
- & geolocation for various types of devices.
- b. Refactor existing codebase to MVVM-C design patten.
- c. Migrate existing application to use rest-based store communication from previously used Open Connectivity Foundation(OCF)

### Raptas Software Inc

Senior Software Engineer

November 2017 - August 2021 (3 years 10 months)

15301 Dallas Parkway, Suite 500 Dallas, Texas 75001

Worked for US Client Korbyt(https://www.korbyt.com), a digital signage company headquartered in Texas.

My Responsibilities includes:

- a. Working on KorbytGO an employee communication-based app.
- b. Worked on NVIDIA Shield Android for Korbyt's Embedded Android Player.
- c. Refactored untestable monolithic screens to MVVM architecture with tests.
- d. Incorporate Android Jetpack Architecture Components into existing apps to improve modularity and testability.

## Chalo Technologies Ltd

Mobile Application Developer

October 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Baridhara DOHS

Chalo is a Local Startup Company which provides on demand car reservation facility across Dhaka.

My responsibilities include:

- a. Launched one of the first On-demand car reservation app in Bangladesh.
- b. Develop and Maintain Mobile application according to the

Client's requirement.

## Education

Islamic University of Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (November 2011 - December 2015)

Result: Cgpa 3.55 (out of 4.0)

**RAJUK Uttara Model College** 

High School Diploma, Science · (January 2009 - July 2011)

## Internship

**Empire Group Bangladesh** 

Intern Software Developer: Mobile Development

February 2016 - September 2016 (8 months)

Banani, Dhaka

My responsibilities include:

a. Worked on a Bike ride-sharing mobile application

b. Producing Software specifications

c. Work on google Maps, JSON, REST, Customized UI design, etc.

### **Profile Links**

a) Personal Website: https://rafsanahmad.github.io/

b) LinkedIn profile: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rafsan-ahmad-943543105">https://www.linkedin.com/in/rafsan-ahmad-943543105</a>

c) Stack overflow profile:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/6139861/rafsanahmad007?tab=profile

d) Github Profile: <a href="https://github.com/rafsanahmad">https://github.com/rafsanahmad</a>

e) Hacker Rank profile: <a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/NULL\_0">https://www.hackerrank.com/NULL\_0</a>

f) Leetcode profile: https://leetcode.com/NULL\_0/